DANIEL DUARTE









Summary

Web Developer currently living in Vancouver, Canada. Passionate about new technologies, startup, amazing people and cycling. With a diverse background, I can offer a unique perspective on the development of any project.

Relevant tech skills

MVC model, Ruby on Rails, React.js, AJAX, jQuery, TDD (Rspec), HTML5, CSS3, SASS, LESS, Bootstrap, Semantic, Git, Photoshop, Illustrator, Responsive Design Coding, Full Stack Development.

Recent Projects

Live To Play Sports - Canada's largest and most experienced wholesale distributor of premium bicycles, parts, and accessories. Delivering premium brands to independent speciality bicycle dealers coast to coast.

www.livetoplaysports.com - www.norco.com - www.axiomgear.com

EzPz - Ecommerce platform for furniture and décor for the home, office, and outdoors. Providing a large selection of items to customers located throughout the United States. **www.ez-pz.com**

Fastcasting - WebApp platform for agents to manage background performers (extras), assisting in their work to connect with casting directors of the film industry. Built in Ruby on Rails and makes use of Bootstrap, Semantic and jQuery on the front end, deployed on AWS. **www.fastcasting.herokuapp.com**

Work Experience

Web Developer

Live To Play Sports Sep 2016 - Present | Port Coquitlam - BC

Web Developer / Web Designer - Freelancer

Aug 2016 - Present

- Developing an eCommerce platform for Mozambike, an African Non-Governmental Organization (NGO), using Shopify.
- Creating a platform for english tutors. Using Ruby on Rails, jQuery, React.js, Bootstrap, AWS.

Web Developer (contract)

Ez Etail - Feb 2016 - Jul 2016, North Vancouver | CA

- Rebuilt the ecommerce platform, using PHP, JavaScript, jQuery.
- Created the workflow to upload the code and maintenance in an online repository.
- Created a new website layout.
- Rebuilt the front end making responsive and mobile using Bootstrap and jQuery.

Communication Analyst

Vale (Mining Company) Jun 2012 - Jun 2014 | Mozambique

- Managed the project of creating a training platform for employees, built on Ruby on Rails.
- Created and developed advertising and training videos.
- Produced multimedia and graphic material for internal and external communications.
- Developed and supported internal customer strategy using internal platform.

Art Director / Web Developer

Global Image - Design, Marketing and Communication Feb 2010 - Feb 2012 | Mozambique

- Managed the design and develop team
- Created and developed web sites using WordPress, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Coordinated all aspects of the creation and production of websites (design and development, using HTML, CSS and JavaScript).

Educational Background

CodeCore Developer Bootcamp

Web Development Certificate
October 2015 - December 2015 | Vancouver, BC
An intensive programming 'bootcamp' with a focus on
self-learning techniques and a practical hands-on
approach. 9 week, 60 hour/week full-stack web development bootcamp, learned how to build web-apps using the
latest technologies.

Federal University of Mato Grosso

Bachelor's Degree, Communication November 2002 - November 2006 | Cuiabá, Brazil Graduated in design, media and entertainment industry. Learned the art of storytelling, photography, documentaries and video productions. Editing audio and video.